ふねのまちでも　ありますね～。
させぼの　みなさ～ん
まっててくださいね！
うみのまち
「させぼ」へ　いくんですね～。
ワンダホー！
「させぼ」です。
この　うみを　わたって→
（真方ジン）
私は　神の頭脳を持つ者…
ファイ・ブレインの　オルペウス。
I am the one with the brain of a god,
the Phi Brain, Orpheus.
（大門カイト）ジン…。
Jin...
（レイツェル）こ…　これは？
What?!
Jin...
ジン!?
There's no escape 'cause I'm now believing my fate
今のは　一体…。
未来…　滅亡の未来…。
What was that just now?
The future... A devastated future.
（井藤ノノハ）
どうしたの？　カイト。
What's wrong?
Kaito? Hey, Kaito!
ねえ…　カイト　どうしちゃったの？
ねえ　カイト！
What's gotten into you? Kaito!
Jin...
ジン…。
（ルーク・盤城・クロスフィールド）
「カイト　そこにいるのは
ジンじゃない。　オルペウスだ！」。
Kaito! That's not Jin! It's Orpheus!
オルペウス!?
Orpheus?
（逆之上ギャモン）オルペウスって…
一体　何なんだよ!?
Orpheus? What do you mean?
話は後だ。
何が起こるか分からない。
We can discuss the details later.
No one knows what's going happen at this point.
Just get away from there for now!
（ルーク）「一旦
その場から離れるんだ！」。
What?
これは…。
But... Why?
そんな…　何で!?
（レイツェル）あっ…。
レイツェル！
Raetsel!
Raerae!
Raetsel...
レイツェル…。
レイツェル…　レイツェル！
Raetsel! Raetsel!
Oh, no...
そ…　そんな…。
あっ!?　い…　今のは未来？
Was that the future?
違う…。
No...
レイツェル…
レイツェルは　どこに!?
Raetsel? Where's Raetsel?
（キュービック）うそだ…　そんな…。
No! This can't be!
Raerae!
（アナ）レイレイ。
レイツェル。
Raetsel...
うぅ…　何やってやがる　カイト！
What are you doing, Kaito?!
てめえなら
レイツェルを救えたはずだろうが！→
You should've been able to save her!
てめえが　あの時　リモコンで鉄球を
落としていれば　レイツェルは…。
If you had let the boulder pass with your controller, she'd be still breathing!
うそだ。　うそだ～！
No! No!
Kaito? Are you okay?
カイト？
大丈夫？　どうしたの？
What's wrong?
やはり　まだ完全ではない。
これが限界か。
So it's incomplete after all. Is this as far I can go?
（エニグマ）な…　何の話だ？
貴様ら　何を言っている!?→
What is going on here?
What are you talking about?
真方ジンではない？　オルペウス？
さっきから　一体　何を…。
You're not Makata Jin?
Orpheus? Did the heat fry your brain or something?
（エニグマ）こ…　ここは!?
This place...
（ラヴーシュカ）どうしたの？　ザガートカ。
（エニグマ）あっ!?→
What's wrong, Zagadka?
あぁ…　ラヴーシュカ！
Lovushka!
早くしないと　お弁当
全部　私が食べちゃうわよ。
Hurry up or I'll eat all the food.
（エニグマ）ラヴーシュカ…。→
Lovushka... Lovushka!
ラヴーシュカ！
何？　変な人。
What? You're such a weirdo.
（エニグマ）ラヴーシュカ…。
Lovushka...
What got into Enigma?
エニグマのやつ　どうしたんだ？
あいつも見たんだ。
He saw it too.
（ジン）貴様には分かるはずだ。
ただの幻ではないと…。
You should understand that it was more than just a mere illusion.
If you obey me, regaining that warmth is not impossible.
（ジン）私に従えば　そのぬくもりを
取り戻す事も　夢ではない。
あ…　まさか…→
What?
Are you telling me Lovushka would...
まさか
ラヴーシュカが生き返るとでも？→
return to life?!
待ってくれ！
（レイツェル）ジン！
Wait!
Jin!
待て！
（リモコンの操作音）
Wait!
ジン！　レイツェル！
（せきこみ）
Jin! Raetsel!
So this Orpheus is that ancient big wig
ねえ　オルペウスって→
あのオルペウス・オーダーが信奉していた
大昔の偉い人？
the Orpheus Order worshiped?
Orpheus as in the poet from Greek mythology?
ギリシャ神話に出てくる
吟遊詩人だよね。
（フリーセル）そのオルペウスと同一人物か
どうかは分からないけど…。
We don't know if it's the same person or not.
But it's clear that he's the ancient genius who made the Puzzle of God and the Armlets.
神のパズルと　オルペウスの腕輪を
作り出した→
古代の天才である事は確かだ。
神のパズルを…。　ほんと!?
The Puzzle of God?
Really?
そいつが　ジンの体を
乗っ取ったってのか？
And he took over Jin's body?
どうにも
信じられねえな。
This sounds unreal.
Yeah. You can't just take over someone's body.
うん。　他人の体を乗っ取るなんて
そんな事　不可能だよ。
The Puzzle of God was a system for Orpheus to achieve immortality.
（ビショップ）
神のパズルは　オルペウスが不老不死を
得るためのシステムだったのです。
不老不死？
Immortality?
According to the Pythagoras Document,
ピタゴラス文書によると　オルペウスは
何らかの方法で　肉体を捨て→
Orpheus managed to somehow throw away his mortal body and become an existence consisting of his mind only.
精神だけの
存在となったそうです。→
そして　神のパズルで　ファイ・ブレインに
限りなく近づいた２人が戦う時→
Then as two people extremely close to the Phi Brain fought in the Puzzle of God,
器として選ばれた方に
オルペウスの精神が　ダウンロードされる。
one of them was picked as the vessel and Orpheus's mind was downloaded to his body.
That's the truth behind the Puzzle of God.
それが
神のパズルの正体。
何だと!?
精神のダウンロード!?
What?
His mind was downloaded?
そんな事　できっこないよ！
How would you even do that? What kind of system is it?
一体　どんなシステムだっていうのさ!?
オルペウスは　僕たちには
想像もつかないほどの→
It just means that Orpheus was a genius beyond our comprehension.
天才だという事だよ。
もし　その話が
本当だってんなら→
Suppose what you say is true, then what is the Writing of God?
神の書ってのは何なんだ？
There has never been a Writing of God.
（解道バロン）神の書など
初めから存在しなかった…。
It seems to have been just the bait to lure people into the Puzzle of God.
（軸川ソウジ）人々を
神のパズルに挑戦させるための→
ただの　おとりだったという事さ。
そんな…。
No way...
（ギャモン）
神の書を　手に入れるために→
Wasn't the POG trying to raise a Phi Brain to get the Writing of God?
ＰＯＧは　ファイ・ブレインを育てようと
してたんじゃねえのかよ！
And my parents died for it too...
そのために
父さんも　母さんも…。
カイト…。
Kaito...
踊らされていたんだ　みんな。→
He fooled everyone. Everyone.
It was all so that Orpheus could return.
オルペウスが復活するためにね。
それで　ジンジンは？
Then what happened to Jinjin?
ジンは　記憶を
失ってたわけじゃないんだ。
Jin didn't lose his memories.
どういう事だ？
What do you mean?
（エニグマ）
記憶を失っていたわけではない？
He didn't lose his memories?
やつは　自らの記憶もろとも
私の精神を　その身に封じ→
That bastard locked away my mind along with his own memories.
復活を阻止していた。
That's how he prevented my return.
そんな…。
No way!
それじゃあ　俺が　ジンの記憶を
取り戻しちまったから→
So it's all my fault that Orpheus returned by making Jin's memories return?
オルペウスは復活したってのか!?
（ギャモン）
で…　カイトが見たっていう幻は？
And what about that illusion Kaito saw?
ピタゴラス文書によると
完全なるファイ・ブレインとなった者は→
According to the Pythagoras Document,
a complete Phi Brain can not only see the future,
未来を見るだけではなく
時間を越え→
but can transcend time and see the past as well.
過去を見る事も
できるようになるらしい。
見るだけでなく　過去に干渉し
未来を変える事もね。
And not only see it. They can interfere with it too, thus changing the future.
えっ!?
人間が　時間を超越？
A human can overcome time? Give me a break!
そんなバカな！
だが　オルペウスは　まだ→
But Orpheus isn't a complete Phi Brain yet.
完全なファイ・ブレインには
なっていない。→
だから
見せる事しかできないんだ。→
That's why he can only show you
オルペウスが過去に干渉した事で
変更された世界をね。
the world as it would be if he interfered with the past.
ただの暗示かもしれないし
トリックの可能性だってある。
It might just be some kind of hypnosis or trick.
あれは…　幻なんかじゃなかった。
（キュービック）えっ？
That was no illusion.
Then what if Orpheus becomes a complete Phi Brain?
それで　もし　オルペウスが　完全な
ファイ・ブレインになっちゃったら？
世界は…　滅びる。
The world will end.
So if you can change the past, I can see Lovushka again?
では　過去を変える事ができれば
ラヴーシュカに会えるのか!?
取り戻したければ　私に従え。
If you want her back, obey me.
ラヴー…　シュカ…。
There is someone I want back as well.
（レイツェル）私も
取り戻したい人がいるんだけど。
（エニグマ）レイツェル。
Raetsel?
世界が…　滅ぶ？
The world will end?
僕たちは見たんだ。
オルペウスが目覚めた瞬間…。
We saw it the moment Orpheus awakened.
We saw a devastated future.
（ルーク）滅亡の未来を。
カイトも見たんでしょ？
ああ。
You saw it too, didn't you, Kaito?
Yeah.
The three closest to the Phi Brain here saw the same future.
ファイ・ブレインに近づいた者たちが
３人とも→
同じ未来を見たという事は
間違いないでしょう。
That should clear some doubts.
で…　でも　その未来は
変えられるんだよね？
But the future can be changed, right?
Kaito's done it before!
前だって
カイトは未来を変えたじゃない！
それは…。
That was...
（モニター・レイツェル）「大門カイト」。
Daimon Kaito.
レイツェル！　お前　無事だったのかよ。
今　どこに!?
Raetsel! You're all right?
Where are you?
「オルペウスと一緒よ」。
With Orpheus.
えっ…。
（ルーク）オルペウスと一緒!?
With Orpheus?
（モニター・レイツェル）
「彼からのメッセージを伝えるわ」。
I have a message for you from him.
Raerae...
Jin's mind is not yet erased.
「ジンの精神は
まだ消滅していない」。
えっ!?
ジンが…　生きてる？
Jin's alive?
Is that true?
本当か!?
「本当よ。→
It is. But there is only one way to save him.
そして　ジンを救う方法が
１つだけある」。
What?
何だよ　それ!?
Me, Kaito, Rook, Freecell, or Gammon.
（モニター・レイツェル）「私　カイト　ルーク　フリーセル
そして　ギャモン。→
この中の誰かが
ファイ・ブレインとして覚醒し→
One of us must awaken as a Phi Brain and offer our brain to Orpheus.
その頭脳を器として
オルペウスに　ささげる事。→
そうすれば　ジンは解放されるわ」。
Then Jin would be freed.
ジンは…　ジンは本当に…。
Would he really?
If you want Jin to return, come to Amgine,
「ジンを復活させたかったら
アムギーネに来なさい。→
そして　オルペウスが用意したパズルに挑み
ファイ・ブレインとして目覚めるのよ」。
challenge the puzzle Orpheus prepares for you, and awaken as a Phi Brain.
Do you believe what Orpheus says?
君は　オルペウスの言う事を
信じるのかい？
「ええ。　私は　やるわ。
ジンが救えるなら…」。
Yes. I'll do whatever it takes to save Jin.
（ルーク）それは　絶対に許さない。
I won't let that happen.
I know you've seen that devastated future as well.
君も見たはずだ
あの　滅亡の未来を。
オルペウスを
ほうっておく事はできない。→
We can't just let Orpheus do as he pleases.
Not to mention, there's no guarantee that doing what he says will save Jin.
そもそも　ジンが助かるという話が
真実だという確証は→
どこにもないだろ。
ルーク…。
Rook...
Then what would you have me do?
（モニター・レイツェル）「だったら
どうしろっていうの!?→
他に　ジンを救う方法は
ないのよ！→
Do you know any other way to save Jin? I sure don't!
ジンがいないなら…
どんな未来も　おんなじよ」。
Without Jin, it doesn't matter what the future holds.
（モニター・ジン）「愚かな」。
Fool.
Jin!
ジン！
You were born in this world.
「この世に生まれたからには
神々に挑み　神々を超える。→
Challenge the gods and exceed them.
それが　人の進むべき道。→
That is the path men are meant to follow.
私は　神々が創りし
『世界』という名のパズルを解き→
I will solve the puzzle of the gods, known as the world,
and gain the power to transcend the very gods themselves.
神々を超える力を　手に入れる。→
どんな犠牲を払おうともな」。
I'm willing to pay any price required.
私は絶対に　ジンを取り戻す。
I will get Jin back.
そのためなら
悪魔にだって魂を売るわ。
For that, I'll sell my soul to the devil if I have to.
ならば　ファイ・ブレインとなれ。
Then become a Phi Brain and give me your body.
そして　その身を
私に　ささげるのだ。
ありゃあ　ジンじゃねえ。
That wasn't Jin.
ルーク。　俺は　アムギーネへ行く。
Rook, I'm going to Amgine.
カイト！
Kaito!
I feel the same as Raetsel.
俺も　レイツェルと同じだ。
ジンを救えるなら…。
Anything to save Jin.
（ルーク）ビショップ。→
Bishop, request cooperation from Amgine's neighbors to keep a close eye on the country.
アムギーネを厳重に監視するよう
周辺各国に協力を要請するんだ。
Yes, sir.
ルーク？
Rook?
（ルーク）言ったはずだ。→
Weren't you listening? There's no guarantee that sacrificing anything will save Jin.
誰が犠牲になっても
ジンが助かるという確証はない。
Then what should we do?
じゃあ　どうするってんだよ…。
（ルーク）ジンを救い出す
他の方法を探す。
なるほど。
Find another way to save Jin.
I see.
ＰＯＧは　各国政府　世界中の有力者と
パイプを持っています。
The POG has connections with governments and people in power all around the world.
その協力を仰ぎ
アムギーネ共和国を監視する。
Keep an eye on Amgine using their aid.
オルペウスの動きを封じて　その間に
対策を講じるのですね。
You want to lock Orpheus in and think of a solution during that time?
But can you find a way?
でも　方法なんて見つかるの？
（ルーク）分からない。
I don't know.
もし　見つからなかったら…。
What if you can't?
（ルーク）その時は　ジンを…。
If it comes to that, Jin must die.
Rook! What?
ルーク　お前！
（バロン）しかたがありません。
We don't have much of a choice here.
本気か!?　学園長！
Are you serious, Principal?
滅亡の未来を　食い止めるために
他に手段がないというなら…。
If there is no other way to prevent a future of destruction...
軸川先輩まで!?
Et tu, Jikukawa?
As if... As if I'd let that happen!
そんな事…
そんな事　俺が許さねえ！
Kaito!
カイト！
カイト　やめて！
Kaito, stop it!
Didn't Jin save all of us?
俺たちは　ジンに
助けられたんじゃねえのか!?
ジンがいたから
ジンが導いてくれたから→
It's thanks to him and his guidance that we can be here now.
僕たちは　今　ここにいる。
だったら　今度は
俺たちがジンを助ける番だろ！
Then it's our turn now to save him!
That's right.
そうだ。　だからこそ→
That's why we must sort this out ourselves.
僕たちの手で決着をつけなければ
ならないんだ。→
僕にとって　真方ジンは
掛けがえのない大切な人だ。→
Makata Jin is an irreplaceable important person to me as well.
でも　今の僕は
ＰＯＧの管理官なんだ。→
However,
I am the chief of the POG now.
ＰＯＧが招いた結果に
対処する責任がある。
I have a duty to handle issues that result from the POG's actions.
Kaito!
カイト！
カイト。
Kaito...
ルーク君も…。
Rook...
I'm sure that he's—
ルーク君だって　きっと…。
分かってるよ。
I know.
He's gotten strong.
あいつ　強くなったよな。
Kaito?
カイト…。
だけどよ　このまま
ジンをほうっておくなんて→
But still, I can't just abandon Jin like this.
俺には　できねえ。
でも　どうするの？
But what are you going to do?
（フリーセル）オルペウスが言っていたろ？
フリーセル。
Remember what Orpheus said?
Freecell?
He wants to solve the puzzle of the gods, known as the world, and gain the power to transcend the very gods themselves.
世界というパズルを解いて
神々を超える力を　手に入れる。→
He's willing to pay any price for that.
そのためなら　どんな犠牲を
払っても構わないって。
うん。　よく意味は
分からなかったけど…。
Yeah... I don't really know what that means though.
（フリーセル）
僕にも　正確な事は分からない。→
Neither do I.
けど　彼以外の誰かが　先に
ファイ・ブレインとして完全に覚醒して→
But if someone can awaken as a Phi Brain before him
世界という名のパズルを
解く事ができれば→
and solve the puzzle of the world,
滅亡の未来は　食い止められる。
then the future of destruction can be avoided.
でも　もし　オルペウスの言う事が
本当だとしたら→
But if what Orpheus says is true,
体を乗っ取られちゃうんでしょ？
then he'd just possess that person's body, right?
（フリーセル）彼を超える力を
手に入れる事ができれば→
If someone can become stronger than him, then maybe he can be stopped.
食い止められるかもしれない。
そうかもしれないけど…。
Maybe.
なるほど。
え？
I see.
つまり　勝ちゃいいって事さ。
えっ!?
So we just have to win, huh?
What?
やつの言ってる事が
どこまで本当か分からねえが→
We don't know how much of what he says is true,
要するに　パズルで勝負しろって
言ってんだろ？
but the point is that all we've gotta do is fight him in a puzzle, right?
だったら　パズルで勝てばいいってな。
Then I just have to beat him at puzzling!
Wait, Kaito, you can't be serious.
…って　カイト　まさか？
ああ　行くぜ。　アムギーネへ！
Oh, I am. I'm going
to Amgine!
や…　やっぱり!?
I knew it...
僕も行くよ　カイト。
（カイト　ノノハ）えっ？
I'll go too, Kaito.
君たちの役に立ちたいんだ。
I want to help you.
フリーセル。
ちょ…　ちょっと待ってよ！
Freecell...
Hey, hold your horses!
そんなの　ルーク君が許さないよね？
お金は？　お金は　どうすんの!?
Rook won't let that happen!
What other way is there?
（フリーセル）任せておいて　ノノハ。
Just leave it to me, Nonoha.
Leave it to you? Freecell, what—
だって　「任せておいて」って
フリーセル君！　っていうか…。
（モニター・メランコリィ）
「私専用　プリティーメランコリィ号の→
I hope you enjoy the flight on my private jet, the Pretty Melancholy.
乗り心地は　いかがかしら？」。
お…　落ち着かねえ。
I can't relax here.
おいしいよ　カイト。
It's delicious, Kaito.
メランコリィ　ありがとな。
Thanks, Melancholy.
「別に。　礼には及びませんわ。→
Don't mention it.
No need to thank me.
私も　あの未来を見ましたの」。
I saw that future too.
メランコリィも？
Melancholy?
「あ～んな未来が
現実になったら→
If such a future turned into reality,
my wonderful plans for my life would go down the drain.
私の輝かしい人生設計も
おしまいですわ」。
本当に助かったよ　メランコリィ。
You really helped us out, Melancholy.
（メランコリィ）
あなたの事を許したわけじゃ
ありませんわ　フリーセル。
I still haven't forgiven you, Freecell.
（フリーセル）「え？」。
本当に許してほしかったら→
If you want me to, then beat that Orpheus or whatever his name was and come back in one piece.
オルペウスとかいうのを倒して
無事　帰ってらっしゃい。
Got it?
（メランコリィ）「分かったわね？」。
Thanks, Melancholy.
ありがとう　メランコリィ。
着いたね　カイト。
ああ。
We're here, Kaito.
Yeah. This is the Republic of Amgine.
アムギーネ共和国だ。
Let's go, Kaito and Nonoha.
行こう　カイト　ノノハ。
な…　何？
What?
Hey! Wait, Kaito!
（少女時代のノノハ）
もう！　待ってよ　カイト！
（少年時代のカイト）へへ～ん！
やなこった～い！　ハハハハ。
Catch me if you can!
Come on! Wait, Kaito!
（ノノハ）こら！　待ってってば　カイト！
（カイト）イェーイ　イェーイ！　アハハハハ…。
Preview
Daimon Kaito!
Can you solve my ultimate 3D puzzle?